Agustin Guerra

888-858-6716 | agustinguerra@ufl.edu | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Professional Profile

Highly motivated engineering professional with 5+ years of experience in the transportation industry. Committed to providing high-quality service focusing on innovation, safety, sustainability, operational performance, diversity equity, and inclusion. Currently seeking internship opportunities in Data Sciences

EDUCATION

University of Florida

Gainesville, FL

PhD candidate in Civil Engineering

Aug. 2019 - Expected May 2023

University of Kansas

Lawrence, KS

MS in Civil Engineering

Aug. 2017 - May 2019

Universidad Tecnologica de Panama

BS in Civil Engineering

Panama, PA *Mar.* 2008 – *May* 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Expertise: Transportation Engineering, Statistical Analysis, Operation Research, Machine Learning

Languages: Python, R

Developer Tools: Github, Visual Studio

Libraries: pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2019 – Present

University of Florida

Gainesville, FL

- Develops optimization algorithms for corridors considering automated-vehicles capabilities
- Assists on the implementation of optimization algorithm for isolated intersections
- Assists in the coordination of projects activities to meet deadlines
- Worked on data manipulation using R packages, MICE
- Developed predictive models (Linear Regression, GAMS, Random Forest, Neural Network) for crash estimation,

Highway & Traffic Consultant

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

WSP

Panama

- Provided safety assessment for roadways, interchanges, and intersections
- Developed geometric design proposals
- Conducted earthwork estimation for highway projects

Highway Engineer

Nov. 2012 – Aug. 2017

Louis Berger

Panama

- Developed geometric designs for proposal and as-built drawings for highway projects. Project portfolio comprises several projects in the Latin American region (Panama, Colombia, Honduras, and Peru) adding up to \$3 billion in construction amount
- Coordinated with different departments (geotechnical, hydraulic, and pavement) to meet deadlines
- Developed digital model terrain for highway projects
- Assisted with slope stability analysis
- Supervised and trained drafter team (4 people)

Awards & Service

ITE Student Chapter VP: Coordinated student seminars and ITE activities

Student Representative at the Internal Steering Committee at UFTI: Promoted engagement activities between industry professionals and students

Fulbright Fellowship: Awarded by the U.S Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs to complete a Master's Degree at the University of Kansas

Global Best Project in Roads and Highways: Awarded by the ENR for the Coastal Beltway project in Panama

References

Lily Elefteriadou, PhD: Barbara Goldsby Professor, University of Florida Aurora Izquierdo: Civil Structural Engineer II, WSP Juliana Canas: Senior Advisor, First Climate

Julio Aysa: Env./Social and Governance Lead Officer, IDB

 $elefter@ce.ufl.edu\\ Aurora.Izquierdo@wsp.com\\ juliana.canas-vanegas@firstclimate.com\\ jaysa71@yahoo.com.mx$